<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crypto Currency Certification Consortium (C4) on Charles Lee</title>
    <link>https://charlesjlee.github.io/test/tags/crypto-currency-certification-consortium-c4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crypto Currency Certification Consortium (C4) on Charles Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://charlesjlee.github.io/test/tags/crypto-currency-certification-consortium-c4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>C4&#39;s CBP Bitcoin certification - 9 months later</title>
      <link>https://charlesjlee.github.io/test/post/20171210-c4-cbp-9-months-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charlesjlee.github.io/test/post/20171210-c4-cbp-9-months-later/</guid>
      <description>Back in March 2017, I posted about passing the Certified Bitcoin Professional (CBP) exam by C4. I did this partly out of curiosity and partly hoping it would help in a job search for crypto roles. My curiosity was satisfied, my wallet $73 lighter, and no employers seemed to care. Not surprisingly, what did help during my job search were my understanding of Bitcoin and my crypto sideprojects.
There is a more technical CBX (Certified Bitcoin Expert) exam intended for developers that looks promising: it covers the API and scripting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts on Crypto Currency Certification Consortium&#39;s (C4&#39;s) Certified Bitcoin Professional (CBP) certification</title>
      <link>https://charlesjlee.github.io/test/post/20170301-c4-certified-bitcoin-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charlesjlee.github.io/test/post/20170301-c4-certified-bitcoin-professional/</guid>
      <description>What is this? The Crypto Currency Certification Consortium (C4) is a non-profit organization that issues Bitcoin certifications. Currently, the only certification they offer is the Certified Bitcoin Professional (CBP), though a more advanced version, the Certified Bitcoin Expert (CBX), is being developed. Given Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s decentralized nature, there can be no official certifying authority &amp;ndash; anyone can issue anything. In this environment, the only thing that carries weight is reputation, and C4 has a solid roster on their board and advisors, including Andreas M.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>