<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Charles Lee</title>
    <link>http://charlesjlee.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Charles Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://charlesjlee.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin beacon: using the blockchain to generate random bits</title>
      <link>http://charlesjlee.com/post/bitcoin-beacon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://charlesjlee.com/post/bitcoin-beacon/</guid>
      <description>Random beacons A random beacon is &amp;ldquo;a trusted service that broadcasts fresh random numbers at regular intervals&amp;rdquo;. Random beacons are useful in situations that demand security against manipulation, e.g. choosing precincts to audit after an election. Several beacon services currently exist, notably Random.org and the NIST beacon, however there are several advantages to using the Bitcoin blockchain as a source of randomness:
 Publicly verifiable  Bitcoin blocks are public as soon as they are mined so anyone can perform and verify the beacon computations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursera review: Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency Technologies</title>
      <link>http://charlesjlee.com/post/bitcoin-coursera-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://charlesjlee.com/post/bitcoin-coursera-review/</guid>
      <description>The Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency Technologies Coursera is an 11-week, 4-lecturer collaboration that gives the student an overview of the existing cryptocurrency environment and how it came to be. It begins with a history of cryptocurrency advancements leading up to Bitcoin, then goes into the technical details of how Bitcoin works, moves on to the societal impact of cryptocurrencies, and finally ends with a discussion of future developments and their feasibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts on Crypto Currency Certification Consortium&#39;s (C4&#39;s) Certified Bitcoin Professional (CBP) certification</title>
      <link>http://charlesjlee.com/post/c4-certified-bitcoin-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://charlesjlee.com/post/c4-certified-bitcoin-professional/</guid>
      <description>What is this? The Crypto Currency Certification Consortium (C4) is a non-profit organization that issues Bitcoin certifications. Currently, the only certification they offer is the Certified Bitcoin Professional (CBP), though a more advanced version, the Certified Bitcoin Expert (CBX), is being developed. Given Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s decentralized nature, there can be no official certifying authority &amp;ndash; anyone can issue anything. In this environment, the only thing that carries weight is reputation, and C4 has a solid roster on their board and advisors, including Andreas M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Steem bot using Python, Piston, and Heroku</title>
      <link>http://charlesjlee.com/post/steem-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://charlesjlee.com/post/steem-bot/</guid>
      <description>Steem for the people When someone writes a great post on Reddit that goes viral and is widely shared, the party that benefits most is Reddit itself. Realizing this and wanting to give back to the community responsible for its success, Reddit toyed with the idea of giving shares of the company to users in the form of a cryptocurrency. This plan was later put on indefinite hold.
Steem is the embodiment of what Reddit wanted to achieve &amp;ndash; a blockchain-based, social news platform where posters and upvoters, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Priorities - Family First</title>
      <link>http://charlesjlee.com/post/2017-priorities-family-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://charlesjlee.com/post/2017-priorities-family-first/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s 11:30pm and I&amp;rsquo;m in the family kitchen by myself munching on a box of palmiers1 with a glass of milk and it dawns on me that I feel uncharacteristically good. I feel safe, calm, clear-headed, and full of food.
Thinking back to my pre-holiday rush to close out everything before 2017, I was over-whelmed, anxious, and really not that productive. With a list of 2017 priorities in front of me, I start planning out the first few months of 2017 and it&amp;rsquo;s soon obvious there&amp;rsquo;s no way I can do all of this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 weeks of Uberman</title>
      <link>http://charlesjlee.com/post/6-weeks-of-uberman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://charlesjlee.com/post/6-weeks-of-uberman/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post is about my experience with the Uberman (UM) sleep schedule, the popularized and extreme polyphasic sleep schedule that achieves 2-3 hours of total daily sleep through periodic 20 minutes naps. The benefits are enticing. Assuming you currently sleep 8 hours/day and follow the 3 hours/day schedule, you can have 21 more hours a week to enjoy and to get stuff done. With all that extra time, surely I&amp;rsquo;d be able to get through my to-do backlog!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>