<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Charles Lee</title>
    <link>https://charlesjlee.com/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Charles Lee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charlesjlee.com/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Experience Learning Prolog</title>
      <link>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20200613-learning-prolog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20200613-learning-prolog/</guid>
      <description>I first heard about the Prolog programming language in the book Seven Languages in Seven Weeks. The book, as promised, introduces the reader to the syntax and paradigms of seven different languages. What attracted me to Prolog was its similarity to constraint programming (programs are defined by and solved using their constraints), its similarity to SQL (data-focused and declarative), and its recursive nature.
Normally, I would learn a new language by playing with it, but Prolog was too foreign and intimidating, so I looked for a more structured learning approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TALE-SPIN in Prolog</title>
      <link>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20200606-tale-spin-prolog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20200606-tale-spin-prolog/</guid>
      <description>TALE-SPIN TALE-SPIN1 is an AI program developed in 1977 by James R. Meehan. It works by using a knowledge base of actions to solve and modify goals. As actions are performed, they output text that form a story. In the words of the author:
 TALE-SPIN is a problem solver, top-down and goal-directed. Its output may be regarded as a trace through problem-solving procedures.
 Meehan rejected previous approaches with clean formulations that involved defining &amp;ldquo;one kind&amp;rdquo; of knowledge but sometimes resulted in bizarre stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chopsticks in Prolog</title>
      <link>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20200605-prolog-chopsticks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20200605-prolog-chopsticks/</guid>
      <description>The Game Chopsticks is a simple game of many variations played by children and college students. The variation I play is:
 two players start by each sticking both index fingers out to represent a count of one on each hand players alternate turns until someone loses by having a count of zero on both hands on a player&amp;rsquo;s turn, he must either:  use one of his hands with positive count $H1$ to tap one of the other player&amp;rsquo;s hands $H2$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static site deployments with Hugo and GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20200517-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20200517-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s been almost two and a half years since I&amp;rsquo;ve updated this website. While I was away, GitHub Actions was released and Hugo jumped from version 0.31 to 0.70! My old Hugo code no longer builds and instead of updating incrementally, I decided it was easier to just rebuild from scratch with the latest version. At the same time, I would update the theme1 I use and integrate GitHub Actions to replace the now-unnecessary deployment script 23.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS Records for GitHub Pages</title>
      <link>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20200516-github-pages-dns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20200516-github-pages-dns/</guid>
      <description>Every once in a while I need to modify my custom domain&amp;rsquo;s DNS records to work with GitHub pages, and every time it&amp;rsquo;s a struggle to get it right. Here I document my currently-working setup.
I followed the recommended setup1 by configuring www as my Custom Domain, also configuring my apex domain, and letting GitHub Pages &amp;ldquo;automatically create redirects between the domains&amp;rdquo;. Specifically for this website, I told GitHub that my Custom Domain is www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin beacon: using the blockchain to generate random bits</title>
      <link>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20170716-bitcoin-beacon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20170716-bitcoin-beacon/</guid>
      <description>Random beacons A random beacon is &amp;ldquo;a trusted service that broadcasts fresh random numbers at regular intervals&amp;rdquo;. Random beacons are useful in situations that demand security against manipulation, e.g. choosing precincts to audit after an election. Several beacon services currently exist, notably Random.org and the NIST beacon, however there are several advantages to using the Bitcoin blockchain as a source of randomness:
 Publicly verifiable  Bitcoin blocks are public as soon as they are mined so anyone can perform and verify the beacon computations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coursera review: Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency Technologies</title>
      <link>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20170301-bitcoin-coursera-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20170301-bitcoin-coursera-review/</guid>
      <description>The Bitcoin and Cryptocurrency Technologies Coursera is an 11-week, 4-lecturer collaboration that gives the student an overview of the existing cryptocurrency environment and how it came to be. It begins with a history of cryptocurrency advancements leading up to Bitcoin, then goes into the technical details of how Bitcoin works, moves on to the societal impact of cryptocurrencies, and finally ends with a discussion of future developments and their feasibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Steem bot using Python, Piston, and Heroku</title>
      <link>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20170108-steem-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charlesjlee.com/post/20170108-steem-bot/</guid>
      <description>Steem for the people When someone writes a great post on Reddit that goes viral and is widely shared, the party that benefits most is Reddit itself. Realizing this and wanting to give back to the community responsible for its success, Reddit toyed with the idea of giving shares of the company to users in the form of a cryptocurrency. This plan was later put on indefinite hold.
Steem is the embodiment of what Reddit wanted to achieve &amp;ndash; a blockchain-based, social news platform where posters and upvoters, i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
